<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Jien Weng</title>
	<subtitle>Jien Weng</subtitle>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.jienweng.com/feed.xml"/>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jienweng.com"/>
  
	<updated>2025-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	
	<id>https://www.jienweng.com/feed.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Small Talk About Hackathons</title>
		<published>2025-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2025-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jienweng.com/posts/something-about-hackathon/"/>
		<id>https://www.jienweng.com/posts/something-about-hackathon/</id>
    
		<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jienweng.com/posts/something-about-hackathon/">&lt;p&gt;Follow-up to my previous hackathon. Actually, I&#x27;ve been to around 8 - 10 hackathons in just one year. And Tbh, I almost always forget that I&#x27;m not even a tech student. I&#x27;m literally not from a tech background in the traditional sense. I&#x27;m just a math student. Most of the coding, building, and all that tech stuff I&#x27;ve done... it&#x27;s purely from passion, the inner drive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way, I&#x27;ve met people who are far more experienced, far more knowledgeable than me. And honestly, I can&#x27;t compete with them. It&#x27;s easy to feel small in those moments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone who&#x27;s been through hackathons, you&#x27;ll know. The amount of time, energy, effort you need to commit is just INSANE. Most competitions require you to go through multiple stages: prelim round, and sometimes a semi-final, and then the final round. Every round is like a mini-marathon, endless brainstorming, last-minute changes, and almost no sleep just to push through and deliver something that works.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first few hackathons, I was genuinely excited. It was fun. Every time one ended, I was already looking forward to the next. But after round and round of hackathons, I started to feel the burn. Exhausted, Emptiness. YES, I still learned something new in every game, but the energy, the excitement just started to wear off.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, it all stated to feel a bit empty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also this lingering thought back in my mind: &quot;Why am I comparing myself to people who are fully in this industry, who live and breathe in tech every single day, when I&#x27;m still just a student trying to explore things outside my field?&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s still one more hackathon coming up, and I&#x27;ll give it what I can. but after that, I really need a break. A proper one. Not just from hackathons, but from the constant cycle of proving myself. I need to breathe, reset and work on my inner health, mentally and emotionally.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not saying I&#x27;m quitting hackathons forever. Not at all. But I know I need some time to focus more on myself, rebuild myself, and come back stronger.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading until here. Sometimes, the best thing you can do for your growth is step back, realign, and then go again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Dead Internet Theory #1</title>
		<published>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jienweng.com/posts/dead-internet-theory-1/"/>
		<id>https://www.jienweng.com/posts/dead-internet-theory-1/</id>
    
		<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jienweng.com/posts/dead-internet-theory-1/">&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been noticing a growing number of AI-generated content, especially on both Reddit and LinkedIn. Not all, but now speaking from the perspective of a student, I found out some of my peers are posting regarding their achievements with some very fancy emojis, and when you see and you can definitely tell that’s AI-generated content. I start doubting how many percentage of the posts are actually really happening because there is a high probability that a bunch of them are just generated by AI that’s actually never happened.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;b77a432b-7713-4b10-879d-e8256d284766?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;You can&amp;#39;t tell whether the experience is real or not&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do admit I used ChatGPT for my content in the past, but I realised that the content is not really what I’ve done before, the experience is basically “artificial”. I don’t deny AI as a productivity tool, but sometimes you just can’t tell the existence of the content written there. There’s a coldness, an emptiness that creeps in when scrolling through these posts, making it feel like shouting into a void where no real person listens.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is really different nowadays to scroll through social media, LinkedIn, and Reddit. You don’t feel people there. It makes me really feel like the dead Internet Theory is here, and everything is full of bot activity and automatically generated content manipulated by algorithms. The authenticity of online interactions seems to be fading, they replaced by automated perfection that feels disturbingly hollow.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chatbots or AI are really good for proofreading, but they are still only good at proofreading. Soon I think they will no longer have real content or real ideas when people are writing their experiences, their ideas; they just become full of BS nowadays. Now I even wish to find some long-ass article that is awfully organised, I find some fun to read through even though it was not good, but I can find authenticity there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has anyone noticed this? You could share them with me or offer me a perspective I haven’t considered before. I’d be more than happy to discuss it. I think we’ll might have another follow-up episode on this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share me your thoughts: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:contact@jienweng.com&quot;&gt;contact@jienweng.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Making Deepseek R1 ChatBot</title>
		<published>2024-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2024-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jienweng.com/posts/deepseek-r1-chatbot/"/>
		<id>https://www.jienweng.com/posts/deepseek-r1-chatbot/</id>
    
		<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jienweng.com/posts/deepseek-r1-chatbot/">&lt;p&gt;Deepseek just boomed—and the AI world is going absolutely wild. Nvidia’s stock took a 15% dive, OpenAI is out here pointing fingers, claiming Deepseek “stole” their data (while they themselves have been scraping everything they can find), and the whole AI ethics debate just got messier. Some call it innovation, some call it theft, but let’s be real—everyone’s been stealing from everyone in this space.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.linkedin.com&#x2F;feed&#x2F;update&#x2F;urn:li:activity:7291035071992520704&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;d66e7a6d-8205-4e9c-ba4f-656971c79857?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;“Good artists copy, great artists steal” - Steve Jobs&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But forget the drama for a second, because the best part? Deepseek is open-source. That’s a huge win for the AI community. No more being locked behind API paywalls or waiting for some corporate overlord to decide what we can or can’t do. It’s out there, free to tinker with, and you bet I had to try it out for myself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I went ahead and do something I wanted to do for soooo long -- built a chatbot. It’s not packed with fancy features (yet), but through this little experiment, I’ve discovered some pretty interesting things about how the Deepseek R1 model works. You can try it out live &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;spaces&#x2F;jienweng&#x2F;chatbot_v2&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;btw, we won’t dive into the technical aspects just yet—that’s coming up in the next section! Stay tuned for more details on how these improvements will work behind the scenes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-unique-thinking-approach&quot;&gt;The Unique &quot;Thinking&quot; Approach&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#the-unique-thinking-approach&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: the-unique-thinking-approach&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What blows my mind the most about this whole setup is how I managed to separate the model’s thinking process from its final response. Most chatbots out there? They just spit out an answer, and you have no idea what’s happening behind the scenes. But with this, you can actually see how the model thinks through a problem before giving an answer. It’s like watching an AI have an inner monologue, refining its thoughts before speaking. And honestly? I’ve never seen this before in any LLMs I’ve used.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I didn’t even plan for this feature—it just happened while I was testing out different ways to improve response quality. I noticed that the model was generating some hidden reasoning steps before its final output. Instead of discarding them, I figured, Why not show them? And once I did, it was a game-changer. It made the AI feel so much more transparent—almost like it was thinking out loud.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;spaces&#x2F;jienweng&#x2F;chatbot_v2&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;b65be583-5569-41e4-ab62-b4bf500120e1?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Fun Fact: The &amp;quot;thinking&amp;quot; parts are actually generated as HTML!&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you ask it something like, “What do you think about climate change in Malaysia?”, you won’t just get a final answer out of nowhere. You’ll actually see the model go through a step-by-step breakdown of its thought process:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking down the question components&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluating current knowledge&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forming logical connections&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synthesizing a comprehensive response&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After seeing the model’s thinking process, what really stands out to me is how structured its response is. It doesn’t just throw out some generic take on climate change—it actually analyzes the question, breaks it down into different angles, and then builds a well-organized answer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;spaces&#x2F;jienweng&#x2F;chatbot_v2&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;6c9e3e2a-d318-4615-8786-7d60248fc049?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Interesting Observation: The model sometimes includes unexpected details—some accurate, some a bit off!&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, while the response does sound solid, there are some oddities that make me wonder what’s going on under the hood. For example, it mentions “the subtropical Andaman and Nicobar Islands”—which, uh, aren’t even part of Malaysia. Also, “Ch bamboo” initiative? Never heard of that one. These small but noticeable mistakes show that while the model is good at structuring its answers, it still struggles with factual accuracy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that’s exactly what makes having a visible thought process so useful. Instead of just blindly trusting AI responses, we can now see how the model arrives at its conclusions—which means we can spot errors more easily. If it had &lt;strong&gt;hallucinated&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; this stuff in a normal chatbot, I might not have even noticed. But because I can watch it reason through the problem, I can tell where things might be going wrong.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;spaces&#x2F;jienweng&#x2F;chatbot_v2&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;8cf44525-7111-4a09-87c7-ee6a09d3cb3b?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;AI Hallucination Meme&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of transparency is what makes AI feel less like a magic black box and more like an actual tool that we can guide, correct, and refine. And that’s honestly what excites me the most about this project.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;deployment-specifications&quot;&gt;Deployment Specifications&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#deployment-specifications&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: deployment-specifications&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chatbot is currently hosted on Hugging Face Spaces, running on a basic-tier instance, which means it’s not exactly a powerhouse but still gets the job done. Here’s what it’s running on:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU: 2 vCPUs&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RAM: 16GB&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage: Basic instance storage&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Framework: Gradio&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inference Optimization: FP16 quantization&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average Response Time: 2-3 seconds&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concurrent Users Supported: Up to 10&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might notice that the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;spaces&#x2F;jienweng&#x2F;chatbot_v2&quot;&gt;live preview&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; here can be a bit slow while generating responses. That’s because the hardware isn’t optimized for LLM inference, so it’s working with some limitations. Hope you can bear with it! 😆&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy the project and want to see it run smoother, you can consider &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;buymeacoffee.com&#x2F;jianrong_jr&quot;&gt;sponsoring me&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Who knows? With enough support, I might upgrade the resources for future projects and push this even further :D&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;efficient-model-architecture&quot;&gt;Efficient Model Architecture&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#efficient-model-architecture&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: efficient-model-architecture&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chatbot uses the Deepseek R1 Distilled 1.5B model, which is a significantly compressed version of the original 685B parameter model. Despite having only 1.5 billion parameters, it maintains impressive performance for many tasks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key points about the model:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Original model: &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;deepseek-ai&#x2F;DeepSeek-R1&quot;&gt;DeepSeek R1 (685B)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distilled version: &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;deepseek-ai&#x2F;DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-1.5B&quot;&gt;DeepSeek R1 Distill Qwen 1.5B&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;440x parameter reduction while maintaining core capabilities&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;blog&#x2F;open-r1&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;8eb746ad-784b-4892-9eb0-4cd26a82af13?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Model Architecture&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;impressive-benchmark-results&quot;&gt;Impressive Benchmark Results&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#impressive-benchmark-results&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: impressive-benchmark-results&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s most fascinating about this model is how well it holds up when compared to much larger models. Despite having far fewer parameters, it manages to outperform some big names in the AI world for certain tasks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;data-science-in-your-pocket&#x2F;deepseek-r1-distill-qwen-1-5b-the-best-small-sized-llm-14eee304d94b&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;2ac19291-5c72-4a60-b290-bd140a61a4d4?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Model Comparison Results&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;outstanding-performance-in-key-areas&quot;&gt;Outstanding Performance in Key Areas&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#outstanding-performance-in-key-areas&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: outstanding-performance-in-key-areas&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AIME 2024 (Math Competition)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DeepSeek R1 Distilled: 28.9% Pass@1&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-4o: 9.3% Pass@1&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claude 3.5: 16.0% Pass@1&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MATH-500 (Mathematical Reasoning)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DeepSeek R1 Distilled: 83.9% Pass@1&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-4o: 74.6% Pass@1&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claude 3.5: 78.3% Pass@1&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Codeforces (Competitive Programming)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DeepSeek R1 Distilled: 954 Rating&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-4o: 759 Rating&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claude 3.5: 717 Rating&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;model-strengths-limitations&quot;&gt;Model Strengths &amp;amp; Limitations&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#model-strengths-limitations&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: model-strengths-limitations&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strengths:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Superior reasoning capabilities, especially in mathematics&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highly efficient with only 1.5B parameters&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective knowledge distillation from larger models&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent performance in zero-shot scenarios&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limitations:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lower performance in general coding tasks&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potential language mixing issues&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensitivity to prompt formatting&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited performance in broader general knowledge tasks&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This balanced perspective shows why I chose this model for my chatbot implementation - it provides exceptional reasoning capabilities while remaining lightweight enough for practical deployment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;try-it-yourself&quot;&gt;Try It Yourself&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#try-it-yourself&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: try-it-yourself&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to iframe restrictions, you can access the live demo through these methods:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;spaces&#x2F;jienweng&#x2F;chatbot_v2&quot;&gt;Direct Link to Demo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;docs&#x2F;hub&#x2F;spaces-sdks-docker#rest-api&quot;&gt;API Documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;spaces&#x2F;jienweng&#x2F;chatbot_v2&#x2F;tree&#x2F;main&quot;&gt;Source Code&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;spaces&#x2F;jienweng&#x2F;chatbot_v2&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;0eab3363-76da-4dab-b44b-a4a5d7cdc96f?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Chatbot interface&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#summary&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: summary&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deepseek has definitely shaken things up in the AI world, and the drama surrounding it is just the tip of the iceberg. Forget the finger-pointing—this move is a win for the AI community, especially since Deepseek is open-source. No more waiting around for companies to decide how we can use AI; now it’s out there for everyone to play with and improve.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as for my little experiment—building a chatbot with the Deepseek R1 model—it’s not feature-packed yet, but it’s definitely been a fun ride. You can try it out live &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.jienweng.com&#x2F;posts&#x2F;deepseek-r1-chatbot&#x2F;(https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;spaces&#x2F;jienweng&#x2F;chatbot_v2)&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and see how it works for yourself!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;additional-resources&quot;&gt;Additional Resources&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#additional-resources&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: additional-resources&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;deepseek-ai&#x2F;DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-1.5B&quot;&gt;Model Card&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;docs&#x2F;hub&#x2F;spaces-overview&quot;&gt;Deployment Guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;spaces&#x2F;mteb&#x2F;leaderboard&quot;&gt;Performance Benchmarks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discuss.huggingface.co&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Community Discussion&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to experiment with the live demo and share your thoughts!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#references&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: references&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DeepSeek R1 (685B)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The original DeepSeek R1 model, a large-scale AI model with 685 billion parameters, was the precursor to the distilled 1.5B version used in the chatbot.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;deepseek-ai&#x2F;DeepSeek-R1&quot;&gt;Source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DeepSeek R1 Distill Qwen 1.5B&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This is the distilled version of the DeepSeek R1 model, compressed to 1.5 billion parameters while retaining core capabilities.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;deepseek-ai&#x2F;DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-1.5B&quot;&gt;Source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open R1 Model Architecture&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Explore the detailed architecture of the DeepSeek R1 model, showcasing its design and structure.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;blog&#x2F;open-r1&quot;&gt;Source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medium - Deepseek R1 Distill Qwen 1.5B Performance&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A comparison of the performance between Deepseek R1 Distilled and other models, showing its impressive results in multiple domains.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;data-science-in-your-pocket&#x2F;deepseek-r1-distill-qwen-1-5b-the-best-small-sized-llm-14eee304d94b&quot;&gt;Source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugging Face Space - Chatbot Demo&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Live demo of the Deepseek R1 chatbot that showcases the model’s response and reasoning capabilities.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;spaces&#x2F;jienweng&#x2F;chatbot_v2&quot;&gt;Source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugging Face - API Documentation&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Official API documentation for Hugging Face Spaces, helping developers interact with models and integrate them into applications.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;docs&#x2F;hub&#x2F;spaces-sdks-docker#rest-api&quot;&gt;Source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugging Face - Source Code&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Direct access to the source code of the Deepseek R1 chatbot project on Hugging Face Spaces for those interested in contributing or learning.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;spaces&#x2F;jienweng&#x2F;chatbot_v2&#x2F;tree&#x2F;main&quot;&gt;Source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugging Face - Model Card&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Official card for the Deepseek R1 Distilled model, providing details on its functionality and training specifications.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;deepseek-ai&#x2F;DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-1.5B&quot;&gt;Source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugging Face - Deployment Guide&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Guidelines for deploying models and applications using Hugging Face Spaces.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;docs&#x2F;hub&#x2F;spaces-overview&quot;&gt;Source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugging Face - Performance Benchmarks&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;An overview of the model performance across various tasks and benchmarks, showcasing the strengths and weaknesses of different models.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;spaces&#x2F;mteb&#x2F;leaderboard&quot;&gt;Source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugging Face - Community Discussion&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;\&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Join the community discussions on Hugging Face, where users can ask questions, share insights, and discuss AI-related topics.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discuss.huggingface.co&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Eco Finance: A Sustainable Future Prototype</title>
		<published>2024-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2024-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jienweng.com/posts/eco-finance/"/>
		<id>https://www.jienweng.com/posts/eco-finance/</id>
    
		<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jienweng.com/posts/eco-finance/">&lt;p&gt;This is a throwback of what happened 2 months ago, but this writing is about the project itself, rather than my experience. For experience wise, you can read the full story here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We participated in PayHack 2024, quite a big hackathon event with many talented individuals.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project, Eco Finance, focuses on the implementation of a carbon tax expected to be released in 2026. Although it initially targets specific industries, it is crucial and trending to implement this for everyone in Malaysia. Read more about the 2026 carbon tax here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European countries are already implementing ESG-centric policies in various industries, such as the automobile industry. These are just preliminary steps; now we want to delve deeper into the subject.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;payhack-2024.vercel.app&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;3034bd0a-9dae-4078-80a9-a641c747b58a?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Eco Finance Interface&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;understanding-the-idea&quot;&gt;Understanding the idea&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#understanding-the-idea&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: understanding-the-idea&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know how much carbon footprint you generate from ordering a Shopee parcel? Or how much carbon you generate by driving to work instead of taking public transport? It&#x27;s challenging for people to visualize their footprint. Hence, we&#x27;re here to make this visible to people, increasing their awareness about this issue. According to Visa, 80% of Malaysians are aware of the environmental impact of consumption. With the release of Malaysia&#x27;s largest payment gateway provider and the latest project linking banks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-it-works&quot;&gt;How it works&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#how-it-works&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: how-it-works&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OpenFinance API can seamlessly integrate people&#x27;s transaction details, allowing us to aggregate a person&#x27;s transactions and their carbon footprints. The calculation would be the emission factor times the amount, giving us the carbon footprint from those transactions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if the emission factor for a specific merchant category is 0.5 kg CO2 per RM, and a person spends RM 100, the carbon footprint would be 0.5 kg CO2&#x2F;RM * 100 RM = 50 kg CO2.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s an established merchant category code (MCC) in transaction details, where we only need to fine-tune and investigate the actual emission factors for each merchant code. This could be done by collaborating with the Department of Statistics Malaysia (DOSM) to conduct surveys and research among Malaysians. In this project, we are using dummy variables based on this ideology only.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;monetizing-the-ecosystem&quot;&gt;Monetizing the Ecosystem&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#monetizing-the-ecosystem&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: monetizing-the-ecosystem&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We circulate this whole ecosystem by monetizing it. We extract carbon credits from them using the formula from WORLDMETER, where the baseline of average carbon emission per person in Malaysia is 8 tons per year. With that, we can pool up carbon credits, extracted from the surplus from the calculation. There&#x27;s a proven market potential with Bursa Carbon Exchange (BCX), established on 9 Dec 2022, which is available to trade carbon credits in Malaysia. Then we sell the carbon credits to major companies in Malaysia like Petronas and Maybank to help them offset their carbon credits. &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.allenandgledhill.com&#x2F;perspectives&#x2F;publications&#x2F;bulletins-malaysia&#x2F;2023&#x2F;bursa-malaysia-launches-voluntary-carbon-market-exchange&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Read more about BCX here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;YouTube id=&quot;1QKwHFVsEXE&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.petronas.com&#x2F;sustainability&#x2F;delivering-net-zero&quot;&gt;Petronas&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, it&#x27;s evident that their future plan aims for net-zero carbon emission by 2050. This proves there is a market in Malaysia, and more people will enter the market and participate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;encouraging-eco-friendly-practices&quot;&gt;Encouraging Eco-Friendly Practices&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#encouraging-eco-friendly-practices&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: encouraging-eco-friendly-practices&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we encourage eco-friendly spending habits in Malaysia? We aim to attract more people, even those who are not initially interested in eco-friendly practices, to join us. We can make Malaysia greener and more sustainable, at least in the sense of ESG. We choose to reward users with healthy spending habits in terms of eco-friendly spending and reward them with cash for being environmentally friendly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;f54512bd-f014-43ac-a1b1-39628b5990d7?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;The whole business plan of eco-finance&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sustainable-business-model&quot;&gt;Sustainable Business Model&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#sustainable-business-model&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: sustainable-business-model&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can summarize the business circulation here and make it sustainable as well, where we can become self-sustaining:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collect carbon credits from users&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pool up carbon credits&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certify carbon credits with Bursa Carbon Exchange (BCX)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sell carbon credits to companies who need them&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reward users to encourage eco-friendly spending habits.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically that&#x27;s it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-random-thingy&quot;&gt;Project Random Thingy&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#project-random-thingy&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: project-random-thingy&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, it&#x27;s about the random thingys of the project. We have the project hosted at this link. Although it is not fully complete, it serves as a prototype and is yet to be an MVP. Considering we had only 24 hours to complete this from idea to execution, I mean, it&#x27;s good for a first-timer. Right...?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can access the hosted project prototype &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;payhack-2024.vercel.app&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to browse through it. If you have any questions, please email me, and I&#x27;ll personally explain it to you. You can also see the admin page by accessing &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;payhack-2024.vercel.app&#x2F;admin&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or by changing the &lt;code&gt;&#x2F;dashboard&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;&#x2F;admin&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. It looks something like this:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;7ee8a2c3-551c-4726-9551-f7d6ab743391?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Admin Dashboard&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to browse through it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrap-up&quot;&gt;Wrap-Up&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#wrap-up&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: wrap-up&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, Eco Finance aims to make carbon footprints visible to individuals, encouraging eco-friendly spending habits and contributing to a greener Malaysia. By monetizing carbon credits and rewarding users, we create a sustainable ecosystem that benefits both the environment and the economy. It&#x27;s really kesian that we couldn&#x27;t make it to final though T.T&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you guys like it :D&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh btw! Once again.. You can read the full story &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;posts&#x2F;first-hackathon-experience&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>First Physical Hackathon Experience</title>
		<published>2024-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2024-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jienweng.com/posts/first-hackathon-experience/"/>
		<id>https://www.jienweng.com/posts/first-hackathon-experience/</id>
    
		<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jienweng.com/posts/first-hackathon-experience/">&lt;p&gt;It was a typical evening when I first saw the announcement for PayHack 2024. &quot;PayNet X JomHack Hackathon&quot;, the banner read, accompanied by logos of PayNet and JomHack. Most people would have scrolled past—after all, hackathons are usually the domain of computer science whizzes and engineering pros. But something made me pause. Maybe it was the challenge, or perhaps it was the nagging feeling that we mathematicians had something unique to offer to the tech world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself staring at my phone, thumb hovering over the share button. &quot;Am I really qualified for this?&quot; I thought to myself. &quot;What if we make fools of ourselves?&quot; The doubts crept in like unwanted guests. But then another voice, stronger and more determined, pushed back: &quot;When else will we get a chance like this? We might not be coders, but we know how to solve problems. Isn&#x27;t that what hackathons are really about?&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reached out to my fellow mathematics coursemates: Janice, Roius, and Gwyn. &quot;Hey, want to do something crazy?&quot; I asked, half expecting them to laugh it off. To my surprise, their responses came quickly, filled with enthusiasm despite (or maybe because of) our collective inexperience. Only 2 of us had ever participated in a hackathon before, and Gwyn had never even written a line of code. But there we were, four mathematics students from UTAR, signing up for one of the most competitive hackathons in the country.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The looks we got when we arrived were priceless. &quot;Are you guys from Computer Science?&quot; someone asked, eyeing our team with curiosity. We exchanged glances and grinned. &quot;Nope, we&#x27;re Math students, haha...&quot; The mixture of surprise and skepticism on their faces was something I&#x27;ll never forget. In those moments, our outsider status felt both terrifying and weirdly empowering.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;25b6ad42-8235-45ae-9505-a2c296a8ca2a?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Our first breakfast together at PayHack 2024 - nervous but excited! The calm before the storm.&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;November 30th marked our first day, and it was a blur of ideation and learning. We came up with an innovative idea: creating an app to visualize transaction carbon footprints, with the ability to pool and trade carbon footprint surpluses with companies in need. On paper, it sounded promising—a perfect blend of fintech and environmental consciousness.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;b16e0c66-cefb-4cc6-8bf6-de5a087cc513?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Getting grilled during our mentoring session - each question pushed us to think deeper about our solution&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came the intense mentoring sessions with Johan Nasir. He didn&#x27;t hold back. &quot;What happens if the carbon credits are manipulated?&quot; he&#x27;d challenge. &quot;How do you ensure the authenticity of the footprint data?&quot; Another round of rethinking. Each session felt like an intense rotan session—tough love at its finest. He&#x27;d poke holes in our solutions, push us to think deeper, and force us to confront real-world problems that actually needed solving.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week before the hackathon was a rollercoaster. Competing against almost 100 teams from across Malaysia, we were shocked to make it to the Top 32. When we saw Johan&#x27;s name among our judges and received the news of our advancement, our excitement was through the roof. But reality quickly set in—we had a major problem. None of us had real web development experience. My knowledge was limited to Python, SQL, and vanilla HTML&#x2F;CSS&#x2F;JavaScript.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With just four days between Tuesday and Friday, we had to make crucial technical decisions while juggling our internships. After intense research, we settled on Vue.js and Flask. Janice even traveled all the way from JB to KL for this. Every evening after our internships, we&#x27;d dive into tutorials, trying to absorb as much as we could about our chosen tech stack.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;0d444922-77c4-4d91-b645-fb96b7fd5d17?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;3 AM and still debugging - running on determination and coffee&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hackathon itself was intense. When exhaustion hit, we took turns napping wherever we could. I couldn&#x27;t get a tent, so I made do with a random bench for quick 4-hour power naps before jumping back into coding. Everything seemed to be going smoothly until the morning of the submission. At 8:30 AM, just after breakfast and 90 minutes before the deadline, our backend crashed—the information couldn&#x27;t be parsed properly. In a desperate move, we had to hardcode some components just to make the submission deadline at 10 AM.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;0784bdc4-dc31-4b2b-9d5a-2e04677a9ba1?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Presenting our final product: MouManTai - tracking and trading carbon footprints from financial transactions&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we didn&#x27;t make it to the Top 10, watching the final pitches was an eye-opening experience. The winning teams showcased solutions that were not just technically impressive but also deeply thoughtful about real-world implementation. One team&#x27;s blockchain-based remittance system particularly stood out - their attention to regulatory compliance and market research was incredible. &quot;We should have done more market validation,&quot; I thought to myself. &quot;Next time, we need to focus not just on the technical solution but on the whole business case.&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top teams also demonstrated masterful presentation skills. Their pitches weren&#x27;t just about features - they told compelling stories about why their solutions mattered. Each slide was carefully crafted, each demo was flawlessly executed, and their responses to judges&#x27; questions showed deep understanding of both technical and business aspects. I made mental notes: &quot;Practice the pitch more. Know your numbers. Be ready for any question.&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite not making the finals, I did win a Samsung monitor in the lucky draw, a small consolation that brought some laughs to our tired team.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;3d119ab7-d3bf-4632-8675-6fbaf1963c08?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;A silver lining - winning a Samsung monitor in the lucky draw!&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back now, the sleepless nights and endless debugging sessions blur together, but certain moments stand crystal clear: the late-night breakthrough when our first feature finally worked, the proud smile on Johan&#x27;s face during our final presentation, and most importantly, the unshakeable bond formed between four mathematicians who dared to dream.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdn.cosmos.so&#x2F;266c9030-58ad-4536-9e60-c88edb6df8a9?format=jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Jien Weng, Janice, Gwyn and Roius&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Janice, Roius, and Gwyn: thank you for taking this leap of faith with me. For believing that our mathematical minds could contribute something meaningful to the tech world. To Johan: your guidance went beyond mentorship—you showed us that innovation comes from daring to be different. And to PayNet and JomHack: thank you for creating a space where even mathematics students could discover their potential in technology.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say the best stories come from stepping out of your comfort zone. Well, we didn&#x27;t just step—we took a giant leap. And while our first hackathon journey has ended, something tells me this is just the beginning of our adventure in the tech world. The equations and formulas we&#x27;ve studied for years are no longer just abstract concepts—they&#x27;re tools waiting to be applied in the vast playground of technology.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, who says mathematicians can&#x27;t be hackers too? Sometimes the best innovations come from those who dare to cross the boundaries between disciplines, who bring fresh perspectives to old problems. And maybe, just maybe, that&#x27;s exactly what the tech world needs more of.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
